My Halime.
Halime.
No.
This is just another game. I don't believe you.
I don't believe you!
What game are you up to?
This isn't a game, Osman.
This is as real as your Bala
who you thought was dead.
And for this moment,
...I have waited too long.
My vengeance is completed.
Everything is over.
Today, you're going to die.
My Halime, is that you?
Halime..
-Meryem.
-My name is...
..Poena.
I've brought your daughter.
...Osman Bey.
Halime.
My daughter.
Damn it, Poena.
Damn it! What's going on with you?
What game are you up to again?
What game?
I don't believe you.
You have to believe, Osman.
I've been waiting for this moment for years.
I didn't plan this in one day.
I thought about every detail patiently.
I took away your daughter from you, Osman.
Halime, is that you?
Is that you, my Halime?
My baby.
-Halime, is that you?
-Look at me.
If you hurt my Halime
If this is true, I will kill you.
I raised your daughter as a true Christian...
...who was hostile against you and your country.
Ask Bala if you don't believe
me. She saw her talisman.
She's right, Osman.
I had written the prayer in it myself.
She's right.
Bala, is that true?
It's Halime.
Her talisman.
How can I make you believe, Osman?
Shall I..
...tell you your daughter's favorite fairy tale?
The wolf and the baby gazelle.
How do you know that?
How do you know?
Your daughter told me, Osman.
If you hurt her.
If you hurt her, I will cut your throat!
Look, Bala.
Osman believes too.
But it's over.
I will never let you two get her back.
All of you are going to die.
Today everything is going to happen as I want.
I won't kill you once but a thousand times.
Bala.
Say goodbye to your daughter.
Halime.
Halime!
The temple's defense has been broken.
I was right about my doubts again.
Osman has entered his
grave, waiting for his death.
In this temple, his heart will crack
from the pain and will be laid at my feet.
Damn it. Damn it! What is happening to you?
Damn it, it was over.
It was going to be over today!
No one can save you from my
hands. You will beg me to die!
We will see who will beg, Osman!
I will kill you!
-Kill them all! -Halime!
Today, not even your corpse will leave here.
Come on brothers! Come on!
You cannot kill me Osman.
I am the only one who
knows where your daughter is.
If you kill me...
...you will...
...never find your daughter.
Never.
You will die!
Halime!
Halime, my daughter! -Bala!
Osman... -Is it Halime?
The burn mark. The burn mark, Osman.
Let me see... No! -No...
No, it's not Halime! It's not...
-Snake...
It's not her.
No, my Halime is alive. My Halime is alive.
Snake..
Where is she?
Where is Halime? Where is she?
-My Bey! My Bey!
Ulugan is coming here. There
are many of them, my Bey.
Mother... Mother! -My son
Thanks to You, my Allah.
-You are alive, mother. -I am.
Orhan.
Thanks to Allah...
I am alright, my son. -You are.
I am alright, thanks to Allah.
Are we going to fight, my Bey?
It doesn't even have a door to defend, brother.
How are we going to fight?
I will shield myself and hold the door, my Bey.
My Bey...
We don't have enough equipment.
There is a chance we won't let them
through, but we will suffer heavy losses.
My brother is right, father.
What are we going to do now? -Today...
...we cannot fight with Ulugan. Come on.
We'll go this way.
Come on, mother.
There are only the dead here, Ulugan.
Osman saved Bala.
Sofia told us that this place was safe.
That witch fell victim to her own arrogance.
Osman..
...must have saved his Hatun, since he ran away.
But their joy will come together with sorrow.
Blood..
My lungs are filled with blood.
They are close.
We will find them.
They will have died before the
blood on their swords gets dry.
Damn it... Damn it... It was going to be over!
They ran away again!
Come closer..
Poena!
Hristo!
Why Poena?
Tell me, why?
Why didn't you attack them?
It was going to be over, you
were going to take your revenge!
Why?!
I was afraid.
Afraid?
Lift your head, Poena.
You were raised to take revenge for your family.
I raised you!
I did!
Why were you afraid Poena? How?!
Revenge...
...is the only thing that keeps me strong.
I was afraid for a moment.
That's all.
I swear to God
...it won't happen again, aunt.
I know it won't, my little bird.
I will do...
..everything I can to fix this.
I will do whatever you ask of me, aunt.
Look Poena.
Turks..
...even in moments of joy,
carry doubts within themselves.
That's why you'll go back to
them and wait for my order.
Don't draw suspicion onto yourself.
What's on your mind?
I have planted such poison in
Osman and Bala's minds that...
...they will walk to their deaths on their own.
Let's have some rest.
Mother... -Children.
Thanks to Allah, you are alive.
Thanks to Allah.
Thanks to Allah. -Uluga
...must be chasing us now.
Let's have some rest first,
then we will leave the forest.
-Stay on alert.
-Okay my Bey.
My Bey.
Your wound is still bleeding, Osman.
We cannot let it bleed.
We have to burn the wound.
Bala, you've treated many of my
wounds. Don't worry. This wound will heal.
But the wound in my heart does not heal, Osman.
We need to find our
Halime, our daughter.
We will find Halime and
take Sofia, don't worry.
Osman!
I was looking for you. Soon...
...the souls of these trees
will be watered with your blood.
-My Bey, they are coming in large numbers.
-They are approaching, father.
We will split our forces
in two. Orhan, Alaeddin...
...you will go to the southern side.
Bala and the others will come with me.
After getting rid of them, we
will meet at the secret tribe.
Yes my Bey. Come on Alps.
Come on.
They split in two.
Which way will we go, Ulugan?
Osman is my prey.
You go after his little dogs.
Osman Bey's Secret Tents
Ulgen, tell them to grind one more sack
of wheat, so we will have enough, alright?
I will tell the Alps now.
After all this pain, it feels like the
tribe has finally found some peace, right?
Right.
Sure they did.
It's the joy and excitement
of the sacred Ramadan.
Now we will only wait for my
father and the others to return.
Tonight, we will have our first suhoor.
My Bala mother would want the
same meal to be served in every tent.
Fatma..
...we will do the same,
my beautiful eyed sister.
We will continue from where
my mother left off, right Fatma?
We will all protect her
trust together, God willing.
Right, sisters?
God willing.
Osman!
You can't run away this time!
Osman, they're coming closer.
We'll handle this with our minds.
Swords won't get out of
sheathes even for vengeance.
Let them come.
They're getting faster.
The spirits of the ground
and the sky are with us, Altuga.
Osman's kin will vanish today.
They're still coming.
-What's your plan, Osman?
-Let them come.
The moment they think they'll
catch us, we will get rid of them.
Come on.
Faster. We won't let them leave this forest.
-We got rid of them, my Bey.
-No, not yet.
But we will.
-Shoot the birds on the tree in the north.
-Alright, my Bey.
Ya Allah!
They're going to the
north. Birds are flying off.
Let's go to the north.
Let's go.
You're going to the north now.
-We almost reached the horses. Come on.
-They're getting closer.
What now, my Shahzade?
We'll show those jackals who
the prey and the predator are.
I know what's in your mind, my Shahzade.
The game with wolves ends with blood.
At the entrance of the pass, we'll
have a welcome party for them.
-Alps, take positions on both sides.
-Alps, grab your bows.
Keep coming.
Ilbay!
Are you looking for us, you dog?
Alaaddin and the others aren't here.
They split up.
-You...
You are a poor dog whose leash
Mongolians are holding, Ilbay!
Who are you to even kill us?
I will skin you, Orhan!
Keep walking to your death.
-Attack!
-Keep coming.
Begum, watch out!
Praise be.
I will skin you, Orhan!
Just be patient!
With this trick, we'll get rid of those fools.
My father must have got rid of Ulugan too.
You jackals... Whoever challenges the lion...
...will be the prey always.
Let's go to the tribe now.
I will make your drown in your blood, Orhan.
You'll drown in your own blood!
I was going to take revenge
from Osman and Bala today.
Look.
There isn't their blood on my hands.
I'll hang all the guards in
the yard to make an example!
Gather all of them.
Fools!
They shouldn't have let them!
Yes, my lady.
Fortunately,
...I poisoned Bala.
They'll fall in my clutches for their Halime.
My lady, Ulugan will hold you
responsible for Osman's escape.
What should we do if he comes to the fortress?
Ulugan.
Ulugan can't take the
risk of losing the alliance.
He's aware of my power.
He already knows turning against each other
instead of destroying Osman would be stupid.
When I punish the idiot guards,
...he will cool down.
Then we will..
...turn the frontiers...
...into hell for Osman together.
Osman Bey's coming!
-Mother?
-Mother...
Mother.
Is... Is this a dream?
For real?
She's alive!
-Mother?
-Is this for real?
-She's really back!
-Mother!
Mother!
Mother! I was so scared!
-Mother.
-I thought we lost you.
This is really you.
-My Fatma.
-Mother.
I haven't gone anywhere, Fatma. I'm here.
This is really you, mother.
How did that happen, mother? Alaaddin!
Orhan, is this a dream?
It's for real, Holofira.
Yet it was a nightmare before.
I don't get it. How did that happen?
Mother, how could you survive?
It was Sofia's game.
She saved me from the fire and imprisoned me.
And Osman Bey saved me from her.
-Father.
My Fatma.
As this is you... Who was
the one who got burned?
What kind of game is this, father?
-Mother...
-My dear.
Praise be, Praise be.
Come on, hatuns.
Bala is exhausted. She should get some rest.
Right, Bala? You should rest.
Fatma, come here.
I'm fine but we need to
cauterize your wound, my Bey.
-Alaaddin, check it out. -No. No need for that.
My wound has recovered.
My father was suspecting
that mother might be alive.
But he didn't want to tell
us before he was sure.
Meryem brought the good news.
Without her, we couldn't
have heard the soldiers.
And we might be still looking for Bala.
Was Meryem with you?
We got worried about her.
We sent Meryem back to
the tribe. Didn't she come?
She didn't.
May Allah protect her. She
may have got into trouble?
-Boran.
-My Bey.
Send alps to search everywhere up to Akhisar.
As you order, my Bey.
Bala, you should rest.
Inform the Beys.
We will have a council.
Where is their damn hidden tribe?
Osman's alps...
...left me somewhere around here.
The tribe should be nearby. But where?
Osman Bey Secret Tents
They think...
...I've fallen weak without a land.
But as long as we have
the fire of faith in our hearts.
...as long as we have hope.
..we will..
...we will never give up.
Well..
If we were to make a move
against Ulugan to take our tribe back
...we would be outnumbered.
Then we should save all the Turkmen Beys like
Sahin Bey living in captivity from Mongolians.
No. It's the first move
Ulugan would predict.
We will..
...take the power on our side
as Ulugan could never imagine.
The power...
...is the leaderless Turkmen...
...beyond our borders.
I see the concern in your eyes.
Tell me what you think.
My Bey.
They are rebellious Turkmen
who never take orders.
So I don't know how we can...
...make them join our fight.
Cerkutay Bey.
Yusuf Bey.
Do you agree Boran Bey on this?
My sons, tell me what you think.
It's hard to get support
from the rebellious Turkmen.
Yet our Bey has always taught us...
There is always a way for those who want to walk
...a lock for those who want to break
and a door for those who want to open.
Allah knows best.
-Do I have permission, my Bey?
-Come in, Kanyumaz.
My Bey, I got important news.
Ulugan demanded a great number of
nokers from beyond the borders, my Bey.
-Yes?
-We have just broken their force.
We can't let them regain strength, my Bey.
We can't but how?
There is definitely a way.
Definitely.
The stone we throw should
both help us get stronger...
...and break Ulugan' wings and legs.
Rebellious Turkmen beyond our borders...
Kanyumaz.
-My Bey.
-Send a message to them.
-As you order, my Bey.
I will be waiting for them in Serinsu.
But...
Ayaz Bey...
You will see Ayaz Bey personally, Boran.
As you order, my Bey.
Osman.
I will be your Azrael, Osman.
I will send you and your dogs...
..to seven layers down, to Erlik Khan.
Where is Osman, Altuga?
He hasn't reached Sogut, Ulugan.
Since he knows we will corner
him there, he keeps moving.
We don't know where he has settled.
We lost many men.
As long as Osman is alive, we will keep losing.
Support noker units must have set out.
Osman doesn't have Alps,
but we have many nokers.
You are right.
We will corner Osman before
he heals his wounds and kill him.
Shut up, Hatun!
Shut up!
Because of your stupidity, Osman is still alive.
Don't think Osman will stop.
Just as he drew Sahin Bey to his side...
...he will make the other Beys side with him.
Have the tribe Beys lost their
minds to join Osman's side?
What did Osman give them except death, Ulugan?
Whatever he gave you he will give them too.
Weren't you deceived by his words in the past?
A wolf changes its fur.
But it never changes its habits.
Osman will not stop.
We will stop him.
Ulugan is right, Begum Hatun.
Ulugan...
...all tribe Beys will be scared of you.
They will not be able to make a decision
when they think about joining Osman's side.
But I know their weak spot.
What are you thinking about, Ilbay?
Osman's treasure is in our hands.
I say..
...we rain gold on Beys.
Let's pull them to our side
with both swords and gold.
The time will come when I
will cover their gold with blood.
Let it be as you say, Ilbay.
Call the Beys. Give them the gold.
My mother.
Mother.
Don't ever leave again, alright?
When you left, the peace of our family was gone.
When I saw my father,
my brothers, and my aunts...
...I thought we would never smile again.
My dear daughter.
Look, it's all over now, huh?
Let me see
Don't shed those pearl tears anymore.
I would sacrifice myself for you.
It's over. It's over now.
All the Turkmens cried and mourned.
May Allah never make us experience
the two days we went through again.
My Gonca! -Mother...
Alaeddin sent an ointment.
Let's apply it to your wounds.
Let's apply it.
Who knows what that demon did to you?
-She is a demon.
She is a vicious demon.
Mother.
You look very tired.
Let's apply the ointment.
And you rest for a while.
That demon caused a deep wound in my heart.
Meryem is coming, mother.
Come on. Come on.
Meryem.
Bala Hatun.
Thanks to Allah!
Thanks to Allah, you are alive!
Thanks to you, my daughter. Osman
Bey told me about the things you did.
But you... Are you alright? Were you hurt?
Mongols attacked.
Alps protected me, I ran away but...
...I couldn't find you since I
didn't know where the tribe was.
Don't be afraid. It's all
over now. You are here.
Meryem.
Your bag is in our tent.
If you need anything,
you can take it from there.
Thank you, Gonca Hatun.
Can I go and rest a bit?
Go.
My beautiful daughter...
Come. Come here.
Since you missed your
mother so much, let me make
you a nice meal with my own
hands, huh? We're hungry.
Your hands are hurt. You are
still bleeding. Don't do it now, huh?
Yes.
Go rest, my Bala. We
will take care of everything.
Yes, Bala mother.
We have even made
preparations for our first suhoor.
Mother, it's Holofira's first
suhoor, that's why she is so excited.
Praise be.
First suhoor, huh? And with your baby.
Thanks to Allah Who let us see the Ramadan.
-Thanks to Allah.
Let's go.
Let's prepare it. Come on.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
Meryem.
Welcome.
Thank you Alaeddin Bey.
Meryem...
...you did us such a favour that...
..from now on..
...from now on, see me as a brother.
Thank you Alaeddin Bey.
No, thank you. Thank you.
From now on, if you have a problem or
need something, come and tell me. Alright?
What is that in your hand?
As I was going to find my dagger, I
found this around the burning cabin.
I was curious about what
it is, so I wanted to ask you.
Good.
I'll keep this.
I'll go and see what it is.
Bala..
You are dressing my wounds
But your wounds...
Look at them...
You haven't even applied the ointment yet.
What have they done to these hands I
couldn't touch? How could they torture you?
She hurt us so deeply that...
...I cannot feel any other pain.
All this pain will pass.
Just like these wounds.
Don't worry.
All the pain in our hearts will disappear.
Our daughter is alive, my Osman.
But she is in that demon's hands.
Who knows how she raised
our daughter all these years?
I still cannot believe it.
How could this happen?
How could that dastard do this? How could she...
...do this to a little girl?
How could she do this to my daughter?
That devil has set such a painful,
such a terrifying game that...
..she waited all those years just to hurt us.
Knowing Halime is alive...
...makes me happy and kills me at the same time.
Without a mother, a father... All alone...
How could this happen, Bala?
Who knows what lies did that...
...dastard dog tell her?
What deep wounds has
she caused in her heart, huh?
"She kept crying.
She asked for her mother
and father", said that devil.
When I imagine her like that...
-Shh, alright.
Alright.
Look, our daughter is alive.
And I will find her and bring her to you.
I will make her pay for every tear
that falls from your gazelle eyes.
Osman, I did not tell our
children since I did not ask you.
What are we going to do? Will we tell them?
Sure we will.
We will, so they will
not mourn for their sister.
They will become hopeful again.
Come on, rest here.
Come on, rest your head here.
Rest so that our hopes can grow too.
This is all the loot we've
obtained from the last raid, my Bey.
The hunt has been fruitful.
You know that the one with the sharpest
sword takes the largest share of the loots.
This is how it should be distributed.
Can I come in, my Bey?
Come in.
Ayaz Bey.
Boran Bey from Kayis is
here. He wants to talk to you.
Osman Bey who lost his lands and
the state sent his most loyal man then.
He will ask us to side with him.
Siding with Osman Bey means
facing the Mongol threat, my Bey.
Let Boran Bey in.
Peace be upon you Ayaz Bey.
Peace be upon you too, Boran Bey. Welcome.
Thank you.
I came here with my Osman Bey's order.
Osman Bey wants to meet you and all
the Turkmen Beys tomorrow at Serinsu.
What does Osman Bey want from us?
I am just a messenger.
You have to go there and hear
directly from my Bey what he has to say.
Tell me Ayaz Bey
Will you accept my Bey's invitation?
My father loves soup made with bone broth.
If we throw it into the pot now,
it will only be ready for suhoor.
We cannot do this, Gonca.
-We can't make it to suhoor.
-No.
We need strength.
We work here, but the Shahzades
are enjoying themselves by the fire.
Alaeddin Bey.
Alaeddin, brother...
You are done, she called you a Bey.
I heard, brother. I heard.
But..
..look.
-Orhan Bey.
-Holofira Hatun.
-I guess you are really tired.
-No.
What happened my Hatun?
Why did you call us?
We go and join battles with you, right?
-Yes, so?
So...
..you will help us while we are cooking meals.
How?
Are we... are we going to prepare meals?
My Gonca, don't... How
is that going to happen...
It is going to happen. Like this.
So...
...this is how it works.
You can make forty valiants
listen to you on the battlefield, but...
...you can't make the
daughters of others listen to you.
Fatma!
Come on.
Let's show how to prepare
and cook meals to them.
-May it be easy.
Let's show them, brother.
Let's do so, but I swear
Alps will make fun of us.
Brother.
Nothing will happen.
Didn't my father also cook for us in the past?
And I remember the days
when you kneaded the dough.
Sister..
She is joking...
Come on.
-Ya Allah!
-Come on.
Are the cauldrons boiling?
Have the meals been prepared?
The Sultan of eleven months
has arrived, how can we sleep?
Don't sleep lazily, get up and do good deeds.
Cerkutay will wake you up, don't worry.
Peace be upon you. No. Sit. Sit.
Peace be upon you too, my Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
We have gone through many storms and troubles.
But thankfully.
...Allah always provided for us.
Today we are in this table
...this is only Allah's gift.
-Thank Allah.
Now..
Fasting doesn't mean only hunger.
It mean sympathizing with the hungry.
It means fighting against your self.
And it means patience.
Bala.
Without you, this house was like an orphan.
Thankfully, my Allah spared your life for us.
-You're here now.
-Thanks to Allah.
Well... May the sahur be fruitful.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
Enjoy your meals.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
Here, my girl.
-Here, brother.
-Thank you, brother.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
-Here, sister.
-Thanks, brother.
Thank you.
Thanks to Allah Who provides us with Ramadan.
-Thanks to Allah.
Thanks to Allah.
-Bala Hatun.
-Yes, girl?
There in the dungeon...
Did that woman do anything to you?
-Were you scared?
-No, girl.
I knew I wouldn't stay in that dark dungeon.
I have a husband who would never leave me there.
That's right. I never would.
-Also, I have a family.
Yes. Yet that woman must
be punished for what she did.
We will never forget that.
She will be.
Holofira, you needn't
have interrupted your sleep.
I didn't want to leave you
alone during your first sahur.
Besides, I want to fast too.
No.
Holofira, you can fast if you want.
She can't. You are pregnant, my dear.
Next time, God willing.
Oh, I almost forgot that.
My mother is right. You can't.
You forgot?
No, Holofira.
You mentioned fasting all of a sudden.
So I got surprised. That's why I said so.
You should eat, my wife.
You should eat in the morning,
in the evening and even at noon.
You have a good appetite these
days. You should eat all the time.
-Brother.
-Are you watching what I eat now, Orhan? -Oh no.
-Sister.
Just eat. It gets worse as you keep talking.
Sister Meryem, pour water
in this for my brother to drink.
Obviously, what he eats today
will burn his stomach tomorrow.
-Alaaddin.
-It will.
Here, brother.
Praise be, Praise be.
Thanks to Allah, we have peace again.
Years ago, a fire broke out in our family.
The ashes of that fire have
turned into a garden of roses now.
Right, Bala?
We have something to tell you.
It's hard to say it.
But it is true.
Your sister Halime...
Halime is alive.
What?
She's alive.
How?
Come, Ayaz Bey.
Tell me.
Did Osman Bey invite you?
Yes, Commander Ulugan.
But I will stand with you.
I'm pledging loyalty to you
and Ilbay Bey from Kayi blood.
You chose the right way, Ayaz Bey.
Your loyalty will definitely be rewarded.
Whoever doesn't get under my wings...
...will burn to ashes with my wrath.
But you will have a long life, Ayaz.
Now tell me.
Where did Osman want to meet you?
In Serinsu.
All the Beys are going to gather there.
Osman will be there too.
You're doing bigger things than yourself, Ayaz.
Now go.
Go where Osman wants to meet
as if nothing had happened here.
When I arrive in there,
..be careful.
Find a cover.
Protect yourself. Don't be killed.
In that council, Osman's head will be cut off.
You shouldn't kill the
other Turkmen Beys either.
Don't be worrying.
We need them alive.
Your reward won't be only the gold.
When you do what we say.
...the castle of Mekece
will be under your command.
-You won't live in a tent anymore.
-Thank you.
Don't worry. Osman will notice nothing.
Now excuse me.
You may leave, Ayaz Bey.
The easiest thing in these
lands are buying men, Ilbay.
Akca's dog will bring death for Osman.
The demon called Sofia...
...has kept our sister away
from us for all those years, huh?
That snake is holding our sister, huh?
Who knows what she did to her for years?
Did she turn her against us?
Doesn't she remember us?
We don't know, my dear.
That snake break our peace and order.
She threw us into the darkness of longing.
Sofia is the key of the secret.
We have to catch her.
Yes, but Sofia knows we'll come for her.
She's going to take measures. It won't be easy.
Even if she goes into a rat
hole, we will find her, mother.
We'll make her suffer much more
than she made us and you suffer.
Speaking of Sofia...
Meryem found this near the cabin.
The sign doesn't look familiar.
It's not from these lands, obviously.
This belongs to Sofia. I saw it in the dungeon.
What is it. Alaaddin?
-I checked, but...
It look complicated, my Bey.
But I will figure out.
Can I have a look?
This is Healer Martin's mark.
He used to visit the temples
and take care of the sick children.
Do you know where he is?
I do.
Maybe, this is the key
that will lead us to Sofia.
Bala, Alaaddin. Visit that healer.
Don't worry. Halime will join our table one day.
We'll take back Halime and our tribe.
I'm taking medicine. Why
do I still have this headache?
Today, you're going to die.
My Halime, is that you?
Mother.
Everything was almost over today.
But I can't.
Like the sword was going to
stick into me instead of Bala.
I don't want, but...
...I can't help it.
I feel like I'm betraying my aunt.
If you hurt my Halime
My God.
When will this suffering end?
I don't know..
...whether you are good or bad for me.
I should visit Healer Martin.
Meryem.
You didn't eat anything.
You can't fast like this.
-Eat some...
-Bala Hatun!
My dear, are you alright?
Let me see you.
Why are you crying?
I am...
When I saw you with the milk
..I remembered my mother.
I miss my mother a lot, Bala Hatun.
My longing never ends.
Oh my wounded bird.
Is Allah punishing me?
Is that why He left me alone?
-I don't have either a mother or a father!
-Not at all.
Don't say such things, my girl.
Look. Our Prophet (PBUH)...
....who Allah most cares for was an orphan.
Allah tests His servants who He cares for.
You aren't alone, anyway. I told you many times.
You are our girl.
I don't have two but three daughters now.
Three?
I mean Halime.
Come on, drink milk.
Azan (caller for prayer) will be recited shortly.
Don't stay hungry.
Osman..
...is smarter than I thought.
Despite all his wounds and weakness,
...his mind never leaves him.
We thought he would save
his alps and Beys in captivity.
But he's gaining power from beyond the borders.
If he were smart, Ulugan,
...he wouldn't rely on those rebels
who care about only gold and money.
He's smart but desperate.
And it's his despair that will
cut off his head here today.
Tell nokers (Mongolian soldiers)
to take positions, Altuga.
As you order, Ulugan.
Come on.
-Son.
My Bey.
Why have you got a sullen face?
Ayaz Bey is alright. But
the other rebellious beys...
I don't know if we should trust them.
It seems you still have my words in your heart.
Well... A Bey should act
with suspicion all the time.
From now on, what we
expect from others isn't trust.
We just expect them to take the right side.
Okay, my Bey.
God is my witness that this is the best quality.
Healer must be around here.
You said it was long before.
You're sure, aren't you?
I'm sure, mother. We're almost there.
Let's pass through this street.
I don't feel well, healer Martin.
I see dreams.
I see dreams even without sleeping.
I don't know...
...whether my visions are my memories...
...or just dreams.
Everything is so confusing.
I listen to someone else's life.
But that person is me in my dreams.
I'm from Byzantine.
I'm a Christian.
But what I see...
Are you taking medicine regularly, Poena?
What is it in this bottle?
When I drink this, none of these happens.
What are you making this of?
I don't understand whether this
medicine is good or bad for me.
Why am I seeing these when I don't take it?
Please tell me.
Why?
This street. I'm sure. One of the shops here.
This is it.
-The same mark.
-Come on then.
In this...
Anyone here?
Bala... Bala..
What do you want?
May Jesus Christ bless you, healer Martin.
We have questions for you.
This bottle was taken from you, right?
You are true Turkmen warriors...
...who are unique and have
solid natures like mountain ranges.
Welcome.
-Thank you, Osman Bey.
-Thank you, but...
We asked Boran Bey but he
said he was just a messenger.
Tell me, Osman Bey. Why did you call us?
Mongolians who cause troubles in the frontiers
and attempt to harm our lives and lands...
...should leave these lands in no time.
I'm here to say that you and I should
follow the same path for this cause.
You're telling us to stand behind
you with all our forces, huh?
No, no.
I'm not telling you to stand
behind me or obey me.
I'm saying we should walk
shoulder-to-shoulder all together.
I'm saying we should clear
these dark clouds all together.
Mongolians are cause troubles
only for the states, Osman Bey.
We just loot here and there.
Mongolians can't find us.
Karesi, Candar, Germiya
...and Kayi.
Mongolians attack the states first, of course.
But remember this.
All those Beys pledged loyalty.
You know me well.
I don't pledge loyalty to anyone.
I would sacrifice my head and life...
...but never kneel.
Now...
...this land's last castle is mine.
The last banner is my banner.
If we fall..
...then the Mongols will march on Turkmens.
When they can't see a state they can take over..
...they will attack you.
Keep talking, Osman
Waste your last breath on this struggle.
Altuga, remember. Beys won't get hurt.
As I said, the bottle is mine.
But I didn't make the medicine inside.
Why would someone put medicine in your bottle?
-Ask where you found it.
-Don't lie.
Princess Sofia. She is our friend.
She said that only you can know this.
I think you have another guest.
The rats have become a real
trouble for me. They are everywhere.
Even the poison didn't help.
Snake poison would surely work.
Keep that in mind.
Since you don't know anything, we
shouldn't keep you busy, healer Martin.
May it be easy.
I promise you loot, gold, and abundance.
My path, for the name of Allah and the
glory of the Turks, is the path of shahada.
Don't forget, this is such a path that...
...it is the freedom cause of those who could
not be captured beyond the iron mountains.
What you say is true Osman
Bey. If not now, then tomorrow.
The Mongols will certainly attack us as well.
-Good.
You said good, but we even came here secretly.
How will we pass our Alps at
the Mongol-controlled border?
Every difficulty has an ease.
Just tell me you accept it.
After you accept it..
...there is a way to get your Alps...
...across our border.
First, your dog will die
Then it's your turn Osman.
My Shahzade!
-Orhan!
-Alps, ambush!
My Bey!
Cerkutay!
Alps!
Come on
Nokers! Let's go to the field! We will fight!
They've hidden countless Alps in the
forest, Ulugan. There are many of them.
I won't leave here until I tear
Osman into a thousand pieces.
Osman and his Shahzade are
dead, Ulugan. I don't want to die here.
-You decide what's going to happen next.
-We are retreating.
Alps! Follow them! Go!
When he heard Sofia's name, he was shocked.
He will definitely make a move.
We will wait.
Holofira.
My daughter.
where is your bottle?
We are fasting, but why aren't you
eating or drinking? Drink some water.
You are pregnant.
I am alright mother, don't worry.
I will drink when I return to the tent.
Someone got out.
So, this is the rat, huh?
We need to find out who they are.
Martin is also going out, mother.
-Alaeddin.
My son, follow that rat. Let's see who it is.
Holofira, Gonca. We will follow Martin.
-Alright mother.
-Yes mother. -Go.
Give this to Master Sofia immediately.
Let's follow the soldier. Let's go.
Alaeddin Bey.
Damn it, she noticed me!
Move!
Stop! Stop! Move! -What is happening?
Move! Move!
Move!
Don't run away! Move!
Move, you man! Move aside!
Where did you go?
Even if you're hiding under
the ground, I will find you.
You escaped now, but you will certainly
fall into my hands, rat. Certainly.
Is everyone alright?
-Thanks to Allah, everyone is alright, my Bey.
All the hatred that has attacked our state and
nation is not enough to scare or control us.
It's not enough to weaken our
determination or chain our necks.
We will teach them this in the harshest way.
What is this situation Osman Bey?
Did you bring us to the
place where the Mongols
set up an ambush saying
we would meet secretly?
What are these armors?
If you knew there would be an
ambush why didn't you tell us?
Don't worry.
The Mongols do not want anything you.
They have a problem with us.
You asked..
...how you would pass the Mongol route.
This ambush is the key to all your
strength, power, and entry into our borders.
We weren't under your command, but our respect
for you is eternal in both worlds, Osman Bey.
Surely, we are with you on this path. Order us.
Thank you Ayaz Bey. Thank you.
Now...
...you will go to Ulugan..
...and reveal the location where
we will meet the Turkmen Beys.
But this..
-What is your intention, my Bey?
-My intention is for you to gain Ulugan's trust.
Once he sees you have sold us
out, he will want to take you to his side.
We will learn when and
where the nokers he called...
...from far away will enter the Kayi borders.
You and the Turkmen Beys will enter
our lands under the guise of nokers.
As Ulugan's army breaks apart..
...our strength will grow
Do your best...
And convince Ulugan.
In Serinsu, you and the Turkmen Beys.
You won't get hurt.
Ulugan's target will only be us.
We, with this plan...
...secured your safety.
Ayaz Bey.
Thank you.
You have also become the leader of this duty.
Not about me, Osman Bey.
This foresight is yours. I
only did what you told me.
Now tell me Beys.
In this important battle,
are you with the Turks?
Your sagacity won't only bring down the Mongols,
it will bring the whole world to its knees.
I am with you with all my strength
along with my Alps, my Bey.
Thank you. Thank you.
Ayaz Bey...
Now you will go to Ulugan.
You will learn...
...where and how his nokers
will pass through the borders.
If he asks about Orhan and me...
...say that we are severely wounded.
-As you order, my Bey.
Holofira, stay behind us. We
will first make that soldier speak.
Come on!
Dastard dog!
Where is the note? You will give that to us!
-Never!
-Speak!
You were going to Sofia, right?
You will tell us everything you know!
-Never!
Where is the note?
Holofira, read this.
Come to the usual place
tomorrow, it's important, it says.
We can only understand
this once we get there, mother.
But first, we need to get this to Sofia.
Let's dress one of the
Alps in this dog's clothes.
We will go after Martin tomorrow.
We will ambush Sofia there.
Come on. Come on, Alps.
My daughter, Halime, I will
take you back from that snake.
We will come together, my child.
-Are we sure Orhan and Osman are dead?
-I'm sure.
Those arrows could even
pierce a pig, Begum Hatun.
Finally, they will die.
Soon we will hear their sala, Begum.
I will send Bala back to where she came from.
Do not be sure they are dead
until you see Osman's corpse.
Ayaz Bey is here, Ulugan.
He wants to see you.
Let him in.
Ayaz Bey...
Are Osman and Orhan dead?
They are still breathing.
But they will breathe their
last, Commander Ulugan.
They cannot survive with those wounds.
You have done a great job, Ayaz Bey.
This happened thanks to you.
If Osman had gathered the Beys to his side,
it would have been hard to defeat him.
Thank you, Ilbay Bey.
But Alaeddin and Bala Hatun are still alive.
I heard you lost many nokers.
That dog..
...and that Hatun.
Do you think they can stand against me Ayaz?
My nokers have already set out.
They will be here soon.
Everyone in that family will die.
If you allow me, I can set out and meet them.
Which way will they come?
Do you think we do not know the way?
Why would you show us the way, Ayaz?
-I... -You...
Do as you are told, don't
interfere with anything else.
Now go, wait for my order.
As you order, Commander Ulugan.
What am I going to say to Osman Bey now?
All those Alps are going
to die because I failed.
Altuga... Where are my nokers?
They are almost at the Karacahisar
borders, Commander Ulugan.
What are you doing here?
I dropped my hat. I was taking it back.
Come, you dastards.
Thank you mother.
Hatun. -Thank you.
My daughter.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
May Allah accept it. -Aameen.
Let's start eating.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
My Bey...
We also left the Alps to watch Martin.
They will report everything he does.
What about the one hiding inside?
-Is there any news from that person, Alaeddin?
-No, my Bey.
It's like the ground split
open and swallowed them.
Since Martin hid that person
he must know who it is.
When we catch him, we will make
him talk and find out, God willing.
Right.
Tomorrow, when they meet, both
Martin and Sofia will be in our hands.
God willing.
My Halime.
We'll find my daughter.
I'll make Sofia suffer much
more than she made me suffer.
Don't worry. We'll do such things to her...
...that she can't go anywhere
before she pays for what she did.
I will cut off her flesh!
I'll make her an example for everyone!
By your leave, I should go.
I have a headache.
Of course, girl. You may leave.
Is it because it's the first day of fasting?
Or are you sick?
I feel sick, but it will be alright when I rest.
If they catch Martin, they will find me too.
If my aunt is caught, they will kill her too.
When Turks killed your family in front of
your eyes, you couldn't stand it, Poena.
You were too young and saw unreal things.
Sofia was worried that you'd lose your mind.
So I worked hard to make this medicine.
I couldn't find a definite cure, unfortunately.
If you don't take it, you will
have those dreams again.
Well..
Is it normal that I see what I hear?
You're affected by what you hear.
Those aren't your dreams.
Your mind is playing games.
Well..
What if I don't take it?
-What happens?
-You'll lose your mind.
Poena? See? It has already started.
Oh good-hearted Sofia.
Her biggest fear is you getting sick again.
Don't forget to take your medicine.
You're so precious to her. Poena.
My aunt is my precious too.
I will ruin your plans.
I will inform my aunt.
You won't be able to catch Martin or my aunt.
I won't let that happen.
Every day Osman and his family are happy,
...I drown in grief, Sofia
This is Commander Lukas' sword.
Like he wants me to kill Osman
and help his soul to find peace.
Whoever waits patiently wins, Hristo.
These are their last peaceful days.
Soon
...our glasses will be filled with blood.
Lady Sofia, he's brought important news for you.
You may leave.
Meryem.
Where are you going?
I couldn't stay in my tent.
I still had a headache
so I wanted to take a walk.
Come here.
You don't have a fever.
We can tell Alaaddin Bey to
prepare some medicine for you.
No, it'll be fine when I walk a little.
Mother, she keeps telling it will fine but
she doesn't take a good care of herself.
Then we will take care of her, Fatma.
She's a girl of this tribe now.
Thank you, but I'm really fine.
I need some fresh air.
Let's get fresh air together then.
Besides, tell me...
What do you want to eat in sahur?
It doesn't matter as long as you cook, mother.
My pretty daughter.
And you, Meryem? I can't cook as
well as your deceased grandmother, but...
...tell me if you crave something.
Thank you, Bala Hatun. I don't crave anything.
Well... It seems you're going to be ill.
Fatma, don't stay here
for long. Go to your tent.
Don't leave her. If she gets
worse, we'll call your brother.
Don't worry, mother. I will keep my eyes on her.
She's my sister now.
-Come on.
Brother.
You said even the sharpest
spears can't pierce it.
You gave us an armor.
And you sent my Bey and
me into the enemy's range.
-And, brother?
And, Alaaddin...
Even with the first arrow hitting my back...
I thought...
"It's over, Orhan."
I thought my heart was broken into two.
Brother.
In the world...
-Yes?
Is there an arrow which can break
this heart harder than even rock?
I don't know, brother.
Harder than even rock?
-Yes.
Harder than even rock,
huh? Harder than even rock!
Harder than even rock, huh?
My sons, may Allah keep
you away from grief and sorrow.
May the light in your eyes never die.
-Aameen, my Bey.
-Thank you, my Bey.
Aameen.
Do I have permission, my Bey?
Come in, Boran.
My Bey, from Ayaz Bey.
My Bey, what's the news?
Do we know anything?
Yes, we do.
Ulugan's nokers...
...are going to enter our lands
through Karacahisar tomorrow.
Tell all the Turkmen Beys
to make preparations quickly.
And wait for us beyond the borders.
We'll take action all together after sahur.
-As you order, my Bey.
As you order, my Bey.
Osman Bey.
Welcome.
Did you take measures as I warned you?
We did, Osman Bey.
All our alps are hiding in the woods.
-Waiting for our call.
-Alright.
Alright.
Now we'll cut off the snake's head and skin it.
Then your alps will enter
my lands with a disguise.
As you order, my Bey.
-Boran.
-My Bey.
Go check it out.
Tell me how many and how cautious they are.
As you order, my Bey.
Near Byzantine Village
Mother.
You're fine, aren't you?
I'm both as happy as a lark...
...and as furious as a fire, Gonca.
For years..
My child was alive but I mourned for her.
Finding the missing is a great gift, mother.
For sure we'll save
our sister from those dogs.
We will.
Like the whole world got shaken...
...and resettled.
Like the wound in my heart never bled.
-My Bey.
-Tell me how many they are.
Why do you keep silent?
Those dogs are too many, my Bey.
They have a regular army.
Hundreds walking one after another.
They're going beyond mountains
and walking towards the pass.
They'll be here before long, my Bey.
Thanks to Allah, we have
a chance to swing swords.
Do you think we can break that army, Osman bey?
They are too many.
We will break.
We will burn them if we have to.
But we won't let them pass.
Tell me.
What do you doubt?
You look cheerful.
We're getting closer to my
sister with every step, my dear.
Don't worry.
-That day is very soon. Scholar.
-God willing. God willing.
I had lost my mother yesterday.
But today...
...we have a great hope right, Trickster Hatun?
Yes.
The healer is coming, mother.
Soon..
We'll be together soon, my child.
Let's see where he goes.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate. Come on.
That is not doubt, Osman Bey. It's the truth.
What is this truth?
Tell us so we can hear it too.
I have no Alp who will be killed for no reason.
We can't fight with all these
nokers. I am not with you.
What are you saying, you coward?
Which tradition allows you to
run away from the battlefield?
Are you teaching us our traditions, Orhan Bey?
A Bey doesn't send his
Alp into a fight he can't win.
I will leave with my Alps as well.
I will rip that...
-My Shahzade.
Yes, a Bey doesn't send his
Alp into a fight he can't win.
A Bey stops the dastards from moving forward.
Even if he is going to die in the
end, he never lets infidels pass.
He does not let them trample down his honour.
We don't need famous Beys...
...we need Beys who will
follow our great cause.
There is no place for cowards like you...
..in our ranks.
Now get lost.
Get lost!
My Bey, allow me. I'll kill them.
Let them Shamil.
Let them
My Bey, the dogs are approaching.
The sound of their footsteps
filled the entire valley.
We only have a few men.
We are facing hundreds of nokers.
What are we going to do now, my Bey?
Come on Sofia. Come.
If she trusts the messenger
we sent, she will come.
What if she realizes we changed the messenger?
Tell me.
What is happening? Who came? What did they ask?
First, Poena came.
She asked me strange questions.
-Poena?
What are they talking about?
What did she ask?
She is remembering things.
The main issue is...
After she left, others came.
They asked about the bottles I gave you.
Who were they?
Come on! -Damn it..
-Sofia.
-Bala.
Now no one can take you from me.
Alps, take the healer.
Sofia.
Snake.
You will pay for every day
you kept my sister away from us.
I will kill all of you.
We won't kill you before you tell
us where my daughter is, Sofia.
But first, I will kill you.
It was almost over, Bala.
You made a big mistake by not dying.
You made that mistake,
Sofia. You made it by living.
You made it by taking my
child. I will make you regret living.
The game is over, Sofia.
Where is my daughter?
If you kill me..
...you will never learn, Bala. Come on.
Kill me!
Come on!
This..
...is the Karacahisar Castle that...
...Osman took with great
effort and lost with my wrath.
This will be the new home of my nokers, Altuga.
Is the castle ready? Tell me.
It is, Commander Ulugan. It is.
The food and water are all ready.
Our soldiers will stay here as they please.
From here, my army
will attack the tribe and
the nearby castles like
lightning with my order.
Once they come, I will
water these lands with blood.
These are Alps. What are they doing here?
We need to inform Ulugan. Come on!
-Come on!
There are Alps in the forest next
to the castle. Commander Ulugan.
Who are they?
We couldn't see their faces
from afar, Commander Ulugan.
Let me go and see, Ulugan.
I'll take their lives and return.
Stop.
We'll go together.
Let's see who these Alps
wandering in my lands are.
We will see.
To horses.
Osman.
I would never think you were dead before
I saw your and your dog's corpses but...
..I also didn't know you could
stand against me like that.
You should have been torn to pieces.
Your arrows can not harm us.
But..
...you will be punished by my sword of justice.
I... I will kill you.
This arrogance will kill you.
You are a miserable man here...
...but you are still being stubborn.
This is what our tradition is.
Turks never kneel before others!
They never receive orders from a dog.
And they cannot be ruled by others!
-You...
...will never change, Osman.
Even if a century passes...
...your arrogance and
stubbornness will remain unchanged.
My ancestor is Oghuz.
My blood is his blood.
My stubbornness is his stubbornness.
Let alone a hundred years...
...even if a thousand years pass...
...it will never change
Never!
But now
...you are facing us.
Now we will see you.
Those who hold a sword die by the sword.
My arrows did not kill you...
...but my sword will kill you now.
Blood! Blood!
We will see.
Meryem.
Are you alright?
I am alright.
You seem upset.
If you have a problem...
...tell me. I'll listen to you.
Walk!
Get up Sofia! Get up! Get up!
Devil!
It will be over today!
Walk!
Bala Hatun is coming.
Now no one will be able to
take you from my hands, Sofia.
You will tell me where my daughter is.
You will take me to my daughter.
Aunt..
Now no one will be able
to save you from me, Sofia.
You will tell me where my daughter is!
Never.
You will never learn, Bala. Never.
You will pay for the pain you caused
to my daughter and to my family, Sofia.
Are you ready Osman?
I am ready.
I always keep my promises...
..and take my revenge.
The Israfil you believe...
..won't blow the trumpet...
...but I will be your apocalypse.
I already killed you Osman.
You don't even know. Turn around.
And look behind you.
Turn around and see well how great my power is.
See, Osman?
My army which will bring the apocalypse to
your lands, your people and your race is here.
So, you set a trap for me, Ulugan.
Ulugan, yes.
Ulugan, who brings the apocalypse.
My glorious, fearless, merciless nokers.
Come here! Come and witness how Osman dies!
I will bury you along with
your glory in history, Osman.
I will destroy you.
This is the Anatolian plateau of Turks.
Here, history is written with blood.
We write history...
...and we change it.
Your words are stronger than your sword, Osman.
You're talking like this by relying on what?
You're desperate.
You're going to die.
I rely on the help of the desperate
and the hope of the hopeless!
And you?
You rely on your army?
Come on fight us. Let's see if you can.
I won't..
I won t.
...give you the honor of dying with my sword.
My nokers are going to kill you. Nokers, attack!
Well... We write history, we break history.
Especially when we say takbir from our hearts!
Allah is the greatest!
Allah is the greatest! Allah is the greatest!
I've been waiting for a long time...
...to say a mouthful takbir
in a tough fight like this!
Come on, brothers! Time to yell!
Allah is the greatest!
Allah is the greatest! Allah is the greatest!
How is that possible?
-Where is my army?
-Deep in hell!
Keep coming here.
Even if they betray and let us down...
...we will never stop against heathens.
Now it's time to destroy nokers. Boran.
Alps, release the flying flames.
Smart move, Osman Bey.
Nokers got ruined. Now we are equal in numbers.
My alps and I will be with you, always.
-Ayaz Bey.
Slaughter the nokers coming in the back.
I will go face Ulugan.
Then wear their clothes and come after me.
As you order, my Bey.
Allah is the greatest!
Come on, alps.
You tried to play games
and tricks against me, huh?
My game ends with blood, though.
Betrayer.
We would never leave the
fate of Turks in your hands!
If there is no peace for us in these lands
there will be no peace for you either.
You will pay for killing my nokers.
Remember.
I'm still the superior one.
Here are the battlefield and Osman Bey.
You are too many but we are Turks.
The bigger they come, the harder they fall.
Now you're going to die.